# Aryan Mehta

London, United Kingdom

m am.career11@gmail.com

07446048446

https://www.linkedin.com/in/am161

https://www.aryanmehta.dev

### Summary

Front-End Developer with 2 years of experience transforming designs and wireframes into high-quality optimised web applications using React.js and building reusable components. Strong proficiency in HTML, CSS and JavaScript/TypeScript; including external libraries and RESTful API handling.

Experience working in Agile and SCRUM methodology.

### **Experience**



# Northcott Global Solutions

**Frontend Developer** 

January 2023 – Ongoing [contract]

- Build an emergency service web platform using React.js, TypeScript and RESTful API.
- Used Google Maps API and their docs to be able to build a custom styled and functional map with advanced concepts such as drawing custom travel paths.
- Used various hooks for optimisation and provided ideas which were implemented in order to maximise the performance and stability.
- Implementation Of OAuth2 Standards.
- Used advanced git flow to manage working in a team.



# Plume – Learning Technology Agency

**Frontend Developer** 

June 2022 – November 2022 [contract]

- Built an e-learning platform with a six-figure budget estimated to be used by 100,000+ users as well as a platform for admins to manage the content.
- Created reusable components and hooks which resulted in quicker frontend development.
- Integrated RESTful API endpoints, which were handled using Axios and React Router.
- Advance state management using React hooks.
- Application fully responsive across all browsers and devices.



- Built an e-learning platform like Duolingo using React.js
- Created reusable components and custom hooks
- Fully responsive across all browsers and devices
- Used SCSS and BEM methodology for styling

## **Education**

The Open

The Open University 2021–2024

**BSc Computing and IT** 

## Qualification

**Royal Greenwich UTC** 2014-2016

**BTEC Engineering Level 3 Diploma** 

**Distinction Distinction** 

### **About Me**

I am currently pursing my qualification during the evenings, which includes Java objectoriented programming, and database management. I like to spend my free time with my friends and at the gym.

### **Skills**

Agile, RESTful API, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Query, Redux, Teamwork, Jira, Scrum, Git, Frontend, UI/UX, Figma, Adobe XD.